Giandeep Singh Phone: +91-9988302017

Behance Profile: <a href="https://www.behance.net/giandeep-singh">https://www.behance.net/giandeep-singh</a> Email: <a href="mailto:giandeep.singh@yahoo.com">giandeep.singh@yahoo.com</a>

#### **Career Objectives**

To promote the goodwill of the company for better output through disciplined, organized and progressive ways with my sincere hard work and utmost endeavors in the task entrusted to me.

## **Professional Summary:**

- Software Engineer with **8+ Years** of Experience in Web & Graphics Designing.
- Web Designing skills using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery.
- Graphic Designing skills using Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator.
- Experience in Designing Web Application, Android/ iOS App, Desktop Application.
- Designed Logo, Mockup, Single Page Brochures, Two fold Brochures, Flex Banner, Table Top.

#### **Professional Experience:**

- Working as Graphics and Web Designer in Vertex Info soft Solutions Pvt. Ltd. from December 2020 till
  date.
- Worked as Software Developer in VeriKraft Solutions Pvt. Ltd. from August 2018 till December 2020.
- Worked as Software Engineer in **BayaTree Infocom Pvt. Ltd.** from September 2014 till August 2018.
- Worked as Graphic and Web Designer in Talentelgia Technologies from October 2013 to August 2014.

#### **Experience Summary:**

Team player Software Engineer with a can-do attitude, phenomenal time management skills, and a strong user focus. Designed Mobile, Web and Desktop Applications.

## Project 1: SMMS (Ships Maintenance Management System) - Web Application

#### **Vertex Infosoft - Company Product**

Role : Web & Graphics Designer

Worked with : HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, Adobe Photoshop, Syncfusion. This application provides features for allowing Ship Maintenance and Management.

## **Roles & Responsibilities:**

• Designed Web UI, Graphics for web UI, worked along with Syncfusion.

#### Project 2: neuvena - Web Application

## **Verikraft - Company Product**

Role : Web & Graphics Designer

Worked with : HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, Adobe Photoshop, Angular 6. This application provides feature for allowing user to make calls using web interface.

#### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

• Designed Web UI, Graphics for web UI and Custom CSS for angular application.

## Project 3: eHealthTrax - Web & Mobile Application

#### **BayaTree - Company Product**

Role : Web & Graphics Designer

Worked with: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, Adobe Photoshop.

This application is used to provide the information of Doctors. Mobile Application provides features of Appointment Booking, Confirmation, Approval and Calendar for Appointments.

## **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Designed Graphics, Splash Screen Design, Icons Used in App, Workflow where Applicable.
- Designed Brochures, Flex Table Front / Top and Flex Banner Stand Design for Advertisement.

# Project 4: eJobSopt - Web & Mobile Application

#### **BayaTree - Company Product**

Role : Web & Graphics Designer

Worked with : HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, Adobe Photoshop

Using this Web Application companies can manage Recruitment process, HR can conduct video Interview and Candidate can connect with HR using his/her Mobile. Using eJobSpot Mobile Notifications can be sent to candidates regarding walk-ins, Current job opportunities.

## **Roles & Responsibilities:**

• Worked as Designing Graphics for Web & Mobile Application.

# **Project 5: Electronic Information Guard - Desktop Application**

#### **BayaTree - Company Product**

Role : Graphics & Application Designer

Worked with : CSS Compatible with JavaFX, Adobe Photoshop

This application is used to protect the personal information of person such as Name, Social Security number and Date of birth etc.

#### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

Worked as Designing Desktop Application Using Adobe Photoshop and JavaFX CSS.

# **Project 6: Sys Admin - Desktop Application**

#### **BayaTree - Company Product**

Role : Graphic & Application Designer

Technologies Used : Photoshop, CSS

This project is used to monitor the resources of System Like (RAM, CPU usage, Number of Process, Empty Disk Space, Used Disk Space) etc.

# Roles & Responsibilities:

• Worked as Designing Desktop Application using Adobe Photoshop and Swing CSS support.

## **Academic Qualification**

Year	Course	College / School	Name of Board/University	Percentage	Division
2013	M.C.A.	CGC Landran	P.T.U.	75	1 <sup>st</sup> (Distinction)
2010	B.C.A.	SASIIT&R Mohali	P.T.U.	69 .71	1 <sup>st</sup>
2007	XII	S.I.S.P.S, Mohali	C.B.S.E.	54.4	2 <sup>nd</sup>
2005	Χ	G.M.S.S.S Sec 46, CHD	C.B.S.E.	56.2	2 <sup>nd</sup>

## **Technical Expertise**

Primary Skills : HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Jquery Graphic Designing, Adobe Photoshop, Angular UI

**Scripting Language** : JQuery, JavaScript

**Project Management** : Jira **Version-control System** : Git

Graphics Software : Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator
Behance Profile : www.behance.net/giandeep-singh

## **Key Skills and Attributes**

Good communication and interpersonal skills.

• Maintaining spirit of leadership.

• Matured enough to handle sensitive information in a professional way.

• Hard working, Enthusiastic, Honest and Punctual.

#### **Personal Information**

Date of Birth : 7 November, 1989
Father's Name : Mr. Ram Singh
Mother's Name : Mrs. Kavaljit Kaur

Nationality : Indian

Languages Known : English, Hindi, Punjabi

**Hobbies** : Playing Badminton, Watching Cricket, Listening Music.

<sup>&</sup>quot;I believe in the principle that "If there is nothing to be struggled, there is nothing to be achieved". And thus strongly believe in putting in my best efforts, giving my loyalty and hard work."